<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="allergy_index">
        <item>Gluten</item>
        <item>Peanut</item>
        <item>Celery</item>
        <item>Crustaceans</item>
        <item>Fish</item>
        <item>Dairy</item>
        <item>Lupin</item>
        <item>Sulphides</item>
        <item>Soya</item>
        <item>Mustard</item>
        <item>Sesame</item>
        <item>Eggs</item>
        <item>TreeNuts</item>
        <item>Molluscs</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--The order of the allergies (not countries/languages) is important as it picks the text based on the order.  Use the english version and allergy index as a reference -->

    <string-array name="English">
        <item>I cannot eat Gluten (present in wheat, barley, rye and oats). Even trace amounts of gluten can make me extremely ill. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Peanuts. Even trace amounts of peanuts can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely. </item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Celery. Even trace amounts of celery can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Crustaceans. Even trace amounts of crustaceans (including crabs, lobster, prawns, scampi and shrimp paste) can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely. </item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Fish. Even trace amounts of fish (including anchovies, salmon, sardines, tuna etc.) can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Dairy. Even trace amounts of dairy (present in butter, cheese, cream, milk powder and yoghurt) can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Lupin. Even trace amounts of lupin can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Sulphides. Even trace amounts of sulphur dioxide (sulphites) can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Soya. Even trace amounts of soya can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Mustard. Even trace amounts of mustard can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Sesame. Even trace amounts of sesame can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Eggs. Even trace amounts of eggs can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Nuts. Even trace amounts of nuts (including cashew, almond, walnut, pecan, pistachio, hazelnut and Brazil nuts) can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
        <item>I have a severe allergy to Molluscs. Even trace amounts of Molluscs (including mussels, land snails, squid, whelks, oysters and oyster sauce) can cause a life threatening reaction. Avoid cross contamination by cleaning all utensils, pans, cooking surfaces and cutting boards. Please verify safe ingredients are used in my meal. Thank you for helping me to eat safely.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Polish">
        <item> nie mogę jeść glutenu (obecne w pszenicy, jęczmienia, żyta i owsa). Nawet śladowe ilości glutenu może mnie bardzo chory. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam silną alergię na orzeszki ziemne. Nawet śladowe ilości orzeszków ziemnych może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię selera. Nawet śladowe ilości selera może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię skorupiaków. Nawet ilości skorupiaki (w tym kraby, homary, krewetki, krewetki i pastą z krewetek) trasa może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam silną alergię na ryby. Nawet ilości ryb (włącznie z anchois, łosoś, sardynki, tuńczyk itp) trasa może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię Dairy. Nawet ilości nabiału (obecne w masło, ser, śmietana, mleko w proszku i jogurt) trasa może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię Lupin. Nawet śladowe ilości łubinu może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię Siarczki. Nawet ilości dwutlenku siarki (siarczyny) trasa może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam silną alergię na soję. Nawet śladowe ilości soi może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię musztarda. Nawet śladowe ilości gorczycy może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię Sesame. Nawet śladowe ilości sezamu może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię na jajka. Nawet śladowe ilości jaj może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię Nuts. Nawet ilości orzechów nerkowca (w tym, migdałów, orzechów włoskich, pekan, pistacji, orzechów laskowych i orzechów brazylijskich) trasa może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
                
        <item>Mam poważną alergię Mięczaków. Nawet ilości mięczaków (w tym małże, ślimaki lądowe, kalmary, whelks, ostrygi i sosem ostrygowym) trasa może powodować zagrażające życiu reakcje. Unikać skażenia krzyżowego, czyszcząc wszystkie naczynia, patelnie, powierzchnie kuchenne i deski do krojenia. Proszę sprawdzić, bezpieczne składniki są wykorzystywane w posiłku. Dziękujemy za pomoc mi jeść bezpiecznie.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Italian">
        <item>Non posso mangiare glutine (presente nel frumento, orzo, segale e avena). Anche tracce di glutine possono farmi molto male. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia alle arachidi. Anche tracce di arachidi possono causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia al sedano. Anche tracce di sedano può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia ai crostacei. Anche tracce di crostacei (tra cui i granchi, aragoste, gamberoni, scampi e pasta di gamberetti) può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia al pesce. Anche tracce di pesci (tra cui alici, salmone, sardine, tonno, ecc) può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia al Dairy. Anche tracce di prodotti lattiero-caseari (presenti nel burro, formaggio, panna, latte in polvere e yogurt) può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia a Lupin. Anche tracce di lupino può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia a solfuri. Anche tracce di anidride solforosa (solfiti) può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia alla soia. Anche tracce di soia può provocare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia alla senape. Anche tracce di senape può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia al sesamo. Anche tracce di sesamo possono provocare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia alle uova. Anche tracce di uova possono provocare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia a Noci. Anche tracce di frutta secca (tra cui anacardi, mandorle, noci, noci pecan, pistacchi, nocciole e noci del Brasile) può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
        <item>Ho una grave allergia a molluschi. Anche tracce di molluschi (comprese le cozze, lumache di terra, calamari, buccini, ostriche e salsa di ostriche) può causare una reazione pericolosa per la vita. Evitare la contaminazione incrociata con la pulizia tutti gli utensili, pentole, piani di cottura e taglieri. Controllare ingredienti sicuri sono utilizzati in mio pasto. Grazie per avermi aiutato a mangiare in modo sicuro. </item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="Turkish">
        <item> I (buğday, arpa, çavdar ve yulafta bulunan) Gluten yiyemez. Hatta gluten miktarları beni son derece hasta yapabilir iz. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben fıstığı için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir fıstık eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Kereviz için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir kereviz eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Kabuklu ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir (yengeç, ıstakoz, karides, scampi ve karides hamur dahil) kabuklu eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Fish ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir (hamsi, somon, sardalye, ton balığı vb dahil) balık eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben süt için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta hayatı tehdit eden bir reaksiyona neden olabilir (tereyağı, peynir, krema, süt tozu, yoğurt içinde mevcut), süt eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Lupin için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir lupine eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Sülfürler için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir kükürt dioksit (sülfitler) eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Soya için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir soya eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Hardal için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir hardal eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben susam için ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir susam eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Yumurta şiddetli alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir yumurta eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Nuts şiddetli alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir (kaju, badem, ceviz, pecan, fıstık, fındık ve Brezilya fındık dahil) fındık eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
                
        <item> Ben Yumuşakçalar ciddi bir alerjisi var. Hatta bir hayatı tehdit eden reaksiyona neden olabilir (midye, kara salyangoz, kalamar, whelks, istiridye ve istiridye soslu dahil) Yumuşakçalar eser miktarda. tüm eşyaları, tava, yemek pişirme yüzeyleri temizleme ve tahtaları keserek çapraz kontaminasyonu engellemek. güvenli maddeler benim yemek kullanılan doğrulayın. güvenle yemek bana yardımcı olduğunuz için teşekkür ederiz. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Romanian">
        <item> Nu pot mânca gluten (prezentă în grâu, orz, secară și ovăz). Chiar și urme de gluten mă poate face extrem de bolnav. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la alune. Chiar și urme de arahide poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la țelină. Chiar si urme de telina poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la Crustacee. Chiar și urme de crustacee (inclusiv crabi, homar, creveți, scampi și pastă de creveți) poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la Fish. Chiar și urme de pești (inclusiv hamsia, somon, sardine, ton etc.) poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la lactate. Chiar și urme de lactate (prezente în unt, brânză, smântână, lapte praf și iaurt) poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la Lupin. Chiar și urme de lupin poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la Sulfuri. Chiar și urme de dioxid de sulf (sulfiții) poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la soia. Chiar și urme de soia poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la muștar. Chiar și urme de muștar poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la susan. Chiar și urme de susan poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severa la oua. Chiar și urme de ouă poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
                
        <item> Am o alergie severă la nuci. Chiar și urme de nuci (inclusiv caju, migdale, nuci, pecan, fistic, alune și nuci de Brazilia) poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
        <item> Am o alergie severă la Moluște. Chiar și urme de moluște (inclusiv midii, melci de teren, calmari, whelks, stridii și sos de stridii) poate provoca o reacție în pericol viața. A se evita contaminarea încrucișată prin curățare toate ustensilele, tigăi, suprafețe de gătit și de placi de taiere. Vă rugăm să verificați ingrediente sigure sunt folosite în masa mea. Vă mulțumesc pentru m-ai ajutat să mănânce în condiții de siguranță. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Dutch">
        <item>Ik kan niet eten Gluten (aanwezig in tarwe, gerst, rogge en haver). Zelfs sporen van gluten kan me ernstig ziek te maken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor pinda\'s. Zelfs sporen van pinda\'s kunnen een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten. </item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor Selderij. Zelfs sporen van selder kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor schaaldieren. Zelfs sporen van schaaldieren (zoals krabben, kreeft, garnalen, scampi en garnalen plakken) kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten. </item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor vis. Zelfs sporen van vis (inclusief ansjovis, zalm, sardines, tonijn etc.) kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor zuivel. Zelfs sporenhoeveelheden zuivel (aanwezig in boter, kaas, room, melkpoeder en yoghurt) kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor Lupin. Zelfs sporen van lupine kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor Sulfiden. Zelfs sporen van zwaveldioxide (sulfieten) kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor soja. Zelfs sporen van soja kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor Mustard. Zelfs sporenhoeveelheden mosterd kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor Sesame. Zelfs sporen van sesam kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor eieren. Zelfs sporenhoeveelheden van eieren een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor Nuts. Zelfs sporen van noten (met inbegrip van cashewnoten, amandelen, walnoten, pecannoten, pistache, hazelnoot en paranoten) kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
        <item>Ik heb een ernstige allergie voor weekdieren. Zelfs sporen van weekdieren (met inbegrip van mosselen, landslakken, inktvis, wulken, oesters en oestersaus) kan een levensbedreigende reactie veroorzaken. Voorkom kruisbesmetting door het schoonmaken van alle keukengerei, pannen, koken oppervlakken en snijplanken. Controleert veilige ingrediënten worden gebruikt in mijn maaltijd. Dank u voor het helpen van me om veilig te eten.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Croatian">
        <item>Ne mogu jesti gluten (prisutna u pšenice, ječma, raži i zobi). Čak i najmanje količine glutena mogu me jako bolestan. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na kikiriki. Čak i najmanje količine kikirikija može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene sigurno jesti.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na celer. Čak i najmanje količine celera može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na rakove. Čak i najmanje količine rakova (uključujući i rakova, jastoga, kozice, škampi i kozica paste) može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene sigurno jesti. </item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na ribu. Čak i najmanje količine ribe (uključujući srdele, losos, sardine, tuna i sl) može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na mliječne. Čak i najmanje količine mliječnih proizvoda (prisutna u maslac, sir, vrhnje, mlijeko u prahu i jogurt) može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na Lupina. Čak i najmanje količine lupine može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na sulfida. Čak i najmanje količine sumpornog dioksida (sulfita) može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na soje. Čak i najmanje količine soje može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na senf. Čak i najmanje količine senfa može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na Sezam. Čak i najmanje količine sezama može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na jaja. Čak i najmanje količine jaja može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na Nuts. Čak i najmanje količine oraha (uključujući kasu, badema, oraha, oraha, pistacija, lješnjaka i brazilski oraščići) može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene jesti sigurno.</item>
        <item>Imam jaku alergiju na mekušce. Čak i najmanje količine školjkaša (uključujući školjke, kopnenih puževa, lignje, morskih puževa, kamenica i kamenica umak) može uzrokovati po život opasna reakcija. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije od strane čišćenje svih posuđe, tave, kuhanje površina i rezanje glačanje. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mojoj obrok. Hvala vam za pomoć mene sigurno jesti.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Vietnamese">
        <item>Tôi không thể ăn gluten (có trong lúa mì, lúa mạch, lúa mạch đen và yến mạch). Ngay cả một lượng gluten có thể làm cho tôi vô cùng ốm. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với đậu phộng. Ngay cả một lượng đậu phộng có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn. </item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với cần tây. Ngay cả một lượng cần tây có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với Động vật giáp xác. Ngay cả một lượng động vật giáp xác (bao gồm cua, tôm hùm, tôm, scampi và mắm tôm) có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn. </item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với Cá. Ngay cả một lượng cá (bao gồm cả cá cơm, cá hồi, cá mòi, cá ngừ vv) có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với sữa. Ngay cả một lượng sữa (có trong bơ, pho mát, kem, sữa bột và sữa chua) có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với Lupin. Ngay cả một lượng nhỏ của một loại đậu có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với sulfua. Ngay cả một lượng lưu huỳnh dioxit (sulphites) có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với đậu nành. Ngay cả một lượng đậu nành có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với mù tạt. Ngay cả một lượng mù tạt có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với mè. Ngay cả một lượng mè có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với trứng. Ngay cả một lượng trứng có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với Nuts. Ngay cả một lượng nhỏ các loại quả hạch (bao gồm hạt điều, hạnh nhân, óc chó, hồ đào, hạt dẻ cười, hạt dẻ và các loại hạt Brazil) có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
        <item>Tôi bị dị ứng nặng với vật thân mềm. Ngay cả một lượng nhỏ các loài nhuyễn thể (bao gồm cả hến, ốc cạn, mực, whelks, hàu và dầu hào) có thể gây ra một phản ứng đe dọa cuộc sống. Tránh lây nhiễm chéo bằng cách làm sạch tất cả các đồ dùng, chảo, bề mặt nấu ăn và thớt. Vui lòng kiểm tra thành phần an toàn được sử dụng trong bữa ăn của tôi. Cảm ơn bạn đã giúp tôi ăn một cách an toàn.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Afrikaans">
        <item>Ek kan nie eet Gluten (teenwoordig in koring, gars, rog en hawer). Selfs klein hoeveelhede van gluten kan my baie siek maak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir grondboontjies. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van grondboontjies kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet. </item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir Seldery. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van seldery kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir Skaaldiere. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van skaaldiere (insluitend krappe, kreef, garnale, garnale en garnale plak) kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet. </item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie om vis te vang. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van die vis (insluitend ansjovis, salm, sardientjies, tuna ens) kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir Dairy. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van suiwelprodukte (teenwoordig in botter, kaas, room, melk poeier en jogurt) kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir Lupin. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van lupiene kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir sulfiede. Selfs klein hoeveelhede swaeldioksied (sulfiete) kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir soja. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van soja kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir mosterd. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van mosterd kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir Sesame. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van sesam kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir eiers. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van eiers kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir neute. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van neute (insluitend cashew, amandels, okkerneut, pecan, pistachio, hazelnoot en Brasilië neute) kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
        <item>Ek het \'n ernstige allergie vir weekdiere. Selfs klein hoeveelhede van weekdiere (insluitende mossels, land slakke, inkvis, whelks, oesters en oester sous) kan \'n lewensbedreigende reaksie veroorsaak. Vermy kruis besmetting deur die skoonmaak van al eetgerei, panne, kook oppervlaktes en sny planke. Bevestig asseblief veilig bestanddele word gebruik in my maaltyd. Dankie vir die hulp om my om veilig te eet.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Finnish">
        <item>En voi syödä gluteenia (läsnä vehnä, ohra, ruis ja kaura). Jopa pieniä määriä gluteenia voit minut erittäin huonosti. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Peanuts. Jopa pieniä määriä pähkinöitä voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti. </item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Selleri. Jopa pieniä määriä selleriä voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia äyriäisiin. Jopa pieniä määriä äyriäisiä (mukaan lukien rapuja, hummeria, katkarapuja, scampia ja katkarapu liitä) voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti. </item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Fish. Jopa pieniä määriä kalat (mukaan lukien anjovis, lohi, sardiini, tonnikala jne) voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Dairy. Jopa pieniä määriä meijerituotteiden (läsnä voi, juusto, kerma, maitojauhe ja jogurtti) voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Lupin. Jopa pieniä määriä lupiinin voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Sulfidit. Jopa pieniä määriä rikkidioksidia (sulfiitti) voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Soija. Jopa pieniä määriä soija voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Mustard. Jopa pieniä määriä sinappi voivat aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Sesame. Jopa pieniä määriä seesami voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Munat. Jopa pieniä määriä munia voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Nuts. Jopa pieniä määriä pähkinöitä (kuten cashew, manteli, saksanpähkinä, pekaanipähkinä, pistaasi, hasselpähkinä ja parapähkinät) voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
        <item>I on vakava allergia Nilviäiset. Jopa pieniä määriä nilviäisiä (mukaan lukien simpukat, maa etanat, kalmari, whelks, osterit ja osterikastike) voi aiheuttaa hengenvaarallisia reaktio. Ristikontaminaation välttämiseksi siivoamalla kaikki astiat, kattilat, paistopinnoilla ja leikkuulaudat. Varmista turvallinen ainesosia käytetään minun aterian. Kiitos, että autat minua syömään turvallisesti.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Norwegian">
        <item>Jeg kan ikke spise gluten (finnes i hvete, bygg, rug og havre). Selv spor av gluten kan gjøre meg svært syk. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot peanøtter. Selv spor av peanøtter kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt. </item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot selleri. Selv spor av selleri kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot Krepsdyr. Selv spormengder av krepsdyr (herunder krabber, hummer, reker, scampi og reker lim) kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt. </item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot fisk. Selv spormengder av fisk (inkludert ansjos, laks, sardiner, tunfisk etc.) kan føre til en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi til meieri. Selv spormengder av meieri (til stede i smør, ost, fløte, melk pulver og yoghurt) kan føre til en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot Lupin. Selv spor av lupin kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot Sulfider. Selv spormengder av svoveldioksid (sulfitt) kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot soya. Selv spormengder av soya kan føre til en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot sennep. Selv spormengder av sennep kan føre til en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi til sesamfrø. Selv spor av sesam kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot egg. Selv spormengder av egg kan føre til en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot nøtter. Selv spor av nøtter (herunder cashew, mandel, valnøtt, pecan, pistasj, hasselnøtt og paranøtter) kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt.</item>
        <item>Jeg har en alvorlig allergi mot Bløtdyr. Selv spor av bløtdyr (inkludert blåskjell, snegler, blekksprut, snegler, østers og østerssaus) kan forårsake en livstruende reaksjon. Unngå krysskontaminering ved å rense alle kjøkkenutstyr, panner, matlaging overflater og skjærebrett. Kontroller trygge ingredienser er brukt i min måltid. Takk for at du hjelper meg å spise trygt du.</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="German">
        <item>Ich kann nicht essen Gluten (in Weizen, Gerste, Roggen und Hafer). Auch Spuren von Gluten kann mich sehr krank machen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Erdnüsse haben. Auch Spuren von Erdnüssen kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich habe eine schwere Allergie gegen Sellerie. Selbst Mengen von Sellerie verfolgen kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Crustaceans haben. Auch Spuren von Krustentieren (einschließlich Krabben, Hummer, Garnelen, Scampi und Shrimps-Paste) kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich habe eine schwere Allergie gegen Fisch. Auch Spuren von Fisch (einschließlich Sardellen, Lachs, Sardinen, Thunfisch etc.) kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Milchprodukte haben. Auch Spuren von Milch (in Butter, Käse, Sahne, Milchpulver und Joghurt) kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Lupin haben. Selbst Mengen von Lupinenverfolgen kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Sulfide haben. Auch Spuren von Schwefeldioxid (Sulfite) kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Soja haben. Auch Spuren von Soja kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Senf haben. Selbst Mengen an Senfverfolgen kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Sesame haben. Selbst Mengen Sesam verfolgen kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Eier haben. Auch Spuren von Eiern kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Nüsse haben. Auch Mengen von Nüssen Spuren (einschließlich Cashew, Mandel, Walnuss, Pecan, Pistazien, Haselnuss und Paranüsse) kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
        <item>Ich eine schwere Allergie gegen Mollusken haben. Auch Spuren von Muscheln (einschließlich Muscheln, Landschnecken, Tintenfische, whelks, Austern und Austernsauce) kann eine lebensbedrohliche Reaktion hervorrufen. Zur Vermeidung von Kreuzkontamination durch alle Utensilien reinigen, Pfannen, Kochflächen und Schneidebretter. Bitte überprüfen sichere Inhaltsstoffe in meiner Mahlzeit verwendet werden. Vielen Dank für die Hilfe sicher zu essen.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="French">
        <item>Je ne peux pas manger de gluten (présent dans le blé, l\'orge, le seigle et l\'avoine). Même des quantités infimes de gluten peuvent me faire très mal. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique grave aux arachides. Même des traces d\'arachides peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à Céleri. Même des traces de céleri peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à Crustacés. Même des traces de crustacés (y compris les crabes, les homards, les crevettes, les langoustines et la pâte de crevettes) peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère pour les poissons. Même des quantités infimes de poisson (y compris les anchois, le saumon, les sardines, le thon, etc.) peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère Dairy. Même des quantités infimes de produits laitiers (présents dans le beurre, le fromage, la crème, le lait en poudre et du yaourt) peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à Lupin. Même des traces de lupin peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à Sulfures. Même des quantités infimes de dioxyde de soufre (sulfites) peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère de soja. Même des traces de soja peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à la moutarde. Même des traces de moutarde peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à Sesame. Même des traces de sésame peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique grave aux œufs. Même des traces d\'œufs peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère aux noix. Même des traces de noix (y compris les noix de cajou, amandes, noix, noix de pécan, pistaches, noisettes et les noix du Brésil) peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
        <item>Je suis allergique sévère à Mollusques. Même des quantités infimes de mollusques peut provoquer une réaction mortelle. Évitez la contamination croisée par le nettoyage de tous les ustensiles, casseroles, surfaces de cuisson et les planches à découper. S\'il vous plaît vérifier les ingrédients sûrs sont utilisés dans mon repas. Je vous remercie de me aider à manger en toute sécurité.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Chinese">
        <item>我不能吃面筋（存在于小麦，大麦，黑麦和燕麦）。即使是微量蛋白量可以让我非常难受​​。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏花生。即使是微量花生量会引起危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。 </item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏芹菜。即使是微量芹菜量会引起危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。我</item>
        <item>有严重的过敏甲壳类动物。即使是微量甲壳量（包括螃蟹，龙虾，对虾，龙虾和虾膏）会导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。 </item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏鱼。即使是微量的鱼量（包括凤尾鱼，鲑鱼，沙丁鱼，金枪鱼等）可引起危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏乳业。即使痕量乳品的量（存在于黄油，奶酪，奶油，奶粉和酸奶）可能会导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏卢平。即使痕量羽扇豆的用量可导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。我</item>
        <item>有严重的过敏硫化物。即使是微量的二氧化硫（亚硫酸盐）量能引起危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。我</item>
        <item>有严重的过敏大豆。即使痕量大豆量可导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏芥末。即使是微量芥末量会引起危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏芝麻。即使痕量芝麻的量可导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏鸡蛋。即使痕量的蛋量可导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏坚果。即使痕量坚果（包括腰果，杏仁，核桃，山核桃，阿月浑子，榛子和巴西坚果）的量可导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
        <item>我有严重的过敏软体动物。即使是微量软体动物量（包括贻贝，土地蜗牛，鱿鱼，海螺，牡蛎和蚝油）可能会导致危及生命的反应。通过清洗一切器具，锅，烹饪表面和砧板，避免交叉污染。请确认安全的成分在我一顿使用。谢谢你帮我放心地吃。</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Czech">
        <item>Nemůžu jíst lepek (přítomný v pšenici, ječmen, žito a oves). Dokonce i stopové množství lepku může dělat mě velmi špatně. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na arašídy. I stopové množství arašídů může vést k život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na celer. I stopové množství celeru může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na korýše. Dokonce i stopové množství korýšů (včetně kraby, humry, krevety, krevety a krevetovou pastou) může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na ryby. Dokonce i stopové množství ryb (včetně ančoviček, losos, sardinky, tuňák atd) může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na mléčné výrobky. Dokonce i stopové množství mléčných potravin (které jsou ve máslo, sýry, smetana, sušené mléko a jogurt) mohou způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na Lupina. Dokonce i stopové množství lupina může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na sulfidy. I stopová množství oxidu siřičitého (siřičitany) může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na sóji. I stopové množství sóji může vést k život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na hořčicí. I stopové množství hořčice může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na Sesame. Dokonce i stopové množství sezamu může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergií na vejce. I stopové množství vajec může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na ořechy. Dokonce i stopové množství ořechů (včetně kešu, mandle, ořech, pekanové, pistácie, lískové ořechy a para ořechy), může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
        <item>Mám těžkou alergii na měkkýších. Dokonce i stopové množství měkkýšů (včetně mušlí, suchozemských plžů, chobotnice, Surmovky, ústřic a ústřicovou omáčkou), může způsobit život ohrožující reakce. Zabránilo křížové kontaminaci čištění nádobí, pánve, povrch vaření a řezání desek. Je třeba ověřit bezpečné ingredience jsou používány v mém jídle. Děkujeme vám za pomoc mi jíst bezpečně.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Indonesian">
        <item>Aku tidak bisa makan Gluten (hadir dalam gandum, barley, rye dan gandum). Bahkan jumlah jejak gluten dapat membuat saya sangat sakit. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Saya memiliki alergi parah terhadap Peanuts. Bahkan jumlah jejak kacang dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Seledri. Bahkan jumlah jejak seledri dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Crustacea. Bahkan jumlah jejak krustasea (termasuk kepiting, lobster, udang, scampi dan terasi) dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah ke Fish. Bahkan jumlah jejak ikan (termasuk ikan teri, salmon, sarden, tuna dll) dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Saya memiliki alergi parah terhadap susu. Bahkan jumlah jejak susu (hadir dalam mentega, keju, krim, susu bubuk dan yoghurt) dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Lupin. Bahkan jumlah jejak lupin dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Sulfida. Bahkan jumlah jejak sulfur dioksida (sulfit) dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Soya. Bahkan jumlah jejak kedelai dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Mustard. Bahkan jumlah jejak mustard dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Sesame. Bahkan jumlah jejak wijen dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Telur. Bahkan jumlah jejak telur dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Saya memiliki alergi parah terhadap Nuts. Bahkan jumlah jejak kacang (termasuk mete, almond, walnut, pecan, pistachio, hazelnut dan kacang Brazil) dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
        <item>Aku punya alergi parah Moluska. Bahkan jumlah jejak moluska (termasuk kerang, siput tanah, cumi-cumi, whelks, tiram dan saus tiram) dapat menyebabkan kehidupan reaksi yang mengancam. Hindari kontaminasi silang dengan membersihkan semua peralatan, panci, permukaan memasak dan talenan. Harap verifikasi bahan yang aman digunakan di makan. Terima kasih telah membantu saya untuk makan dengan aman.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Russian">
        <item>Я не могу съесть клейковины (в настоящее время в пшеницы, ячменя, ржи и овса). Даже следовые количества глютена может заставить меня крайне плохо. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на арахис. Даже ничтожные количества арахиса может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на сельдерей. Даже следовые количества сельдерея может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на ракообразные. Даже следовые количества ракообразных (в том числе крабы, омары, креветки, омары и креветки паста) может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на рыбу. Даже следовые количества рыбы (в том числе анчоусы, лосось, сардины, тунец и т.д.) может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на молочные. Даже следовые количества молочных продуктов (в настоящее время в масло, сыр, сливки, сухое молоко и йогурт) может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на Люпина. Даже следовые количества люпина может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня есть сильная аллергия сульфидов. Даже следовые количества диоксида серы (сульфиты) может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня есть сильная аллергия сои. Даже следовые количества сои может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на горчицы. Даже следовые количества горчицы может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на кунжут. Даже следовые количества кунжут может вызвать угрожающие жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня есть сильная аллергия к яйцам. Даже следовые количества яиц может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на орехи. Даже следовые количества орехов (в том числе кешью, миндаль, грецкий орех, пекан, фисташки, фундук и бразильские орехи) может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли, варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
        <item>У меня сильная аллергия на моллюсках. Даже следовые количества моллюсков (в том числе мидий, земельных улиток, кальмаров, whelks, устрицы и устричным соусом) может привести к угрожающей жизни реакции. Избегайте перекрестного загрязнения путем очистки вся посуда, кастрюли,варочные поверхности и разделочные доски. Пожалуйста, проверьте безопасные ингредиенты используются в моей еде. Спасибо за помощь мне съесть безопасно. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Spanish">
        <item>No puedo comer gluten (presente en el trigo, cebada, centeno y avena). Incluso pequeñas cantidades de gluten puede hacer que me extremadamente enfermo. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia severa a los cacahuetes. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de maní pueden causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad usted.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia severa al apio. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de apio puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a los crustáceos. Incluso cantidades de crustáceos (incluyendo cangrejos, langostas, langostinos, gambas y pasta de camarones) traza puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad usted.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a los peces. Incluso cantidades de pescado (incluyendo anchoas, salmón, sardinas, atún, etc.) traza puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a la lechería. Incluso cantidades de productos lácteos (presentes en la mantequilla, queso, crema, leche en polvo y yogur) traza puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a Lupin. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de altramuz puede provocar una reacción peligrosa para la vida. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a los sulfuros. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de dióxido de azufre (sulfitos) puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a la soja. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de soja puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a la mostaza. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de mostaza puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia severa al sésamo. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de sésamo puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a los huevos. Incluso pequeñas cantidades de huevos pueden causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a los frutos secos. Incluso cantidades de frutos secos (incluidos los de anacardo, almendras, nueces, pacanas, pistachos, avellanas y las nueces de Brasil) traza puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
        <item>Tengo una alergia grave a los moluscos. Incluso cantidades de moluscos (incluyendo mejillones, caracoles de tierra, calamares, caracoles, ostras y salsa de ostras) traza puede causar una reacción potencialmente mortal. Evitar la contaminación cruzada por la limpieza de todos los utensilios, ollas, superficies de cocina y tablas de cortar. Por favor, compruebe los ingredientes seguros se utilizan en mi comida. Gracias por ayudarme a comer con seguridad.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Thai">
        <item>C̄hạn mị̀ s̄āmārt̄h thī̀ ca kin tạng (pạccubạn nı k̄ĥāw s̄ālī k̄ĥāw bār̒ley̒ k̄ĥāw rịy̒ læa k̄ĥāw xót) mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng tạng s̄āmārt̄h thảh̄ı̂ c̄hạn p̀wy māk h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng t̄hạ̀w lis̄ng mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng t̄hạ̀w lis̄ng s̄āmārt̄h thảh̄ı̂ keid pt̩ikiriyā thī̀ khukkhām chīwit h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy</item>
        <item>c̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng run ræng pheụ̄̀x khụ̄̀n c̄h̀ā y mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng p̄hạkchī f̄rạ̀ng s̄āmārt̄h thảh̄ı̂ keid pt̩ikiriyā thī̀ khukkhām chīwit h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng t̀x kûng mæ̂ tidtām primāṇ kûng (rwm thậng pū kûng, kûng Scampi læa kapi) s̄āmārt̄h k̀x h̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yngkār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạ</item>
        <item>c̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng t̀x plā mæ̂ tidtām primāṇ k̄hxng plā (rwm thậng plā katạk plā sælmxn plā sār̒ dīn plā thūǹā‡l‡ ) xāc thảh̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng nm mæ̂ tidtām primāṇ k̄hxng nm (pạccubạn nı ney, chīs̄, khrīm, p̄hng nm læa yo keir̒t) s̄āmārt̄h k̀x h̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng pheụ̄̀x h̄ı̂ lūpin mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng h̄māp̀ā s̄āmārt̄h thảh̄ı̂ keid pt̩ikiriyā thī̀ khukkhām chīwit h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng thī̀ ca sạl fịd̒ mæ̂ tidtām primāṇ k̄hxng ḱās sạlfexr̒ dị xxksịd̒ (Sulphites) s̄āmārt̄h k̀x h̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng thī̀ ca t̄hạ̀wh̄elụ̄xng mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng t̄hạ̀wh̄elụ̄xng s̄āmārt̄h thảh̄ı̂ keid pt̩ikiriyā thī̀ khukkhām chīwit h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng pheụ̄̀x mạs̄tār̒d mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng mạs̄tār̒d xāc thảh̄ı̂ keid pt̩ikiriyā thī̀ khukkhām chīwit h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng ngā mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng ngā s̄āmārt̄h thảh̄ı̂ keid pt̩ikiriyā thī̀ khukkhām chīwit h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng k̄hị̀ mæ̂ tidtām primāṇ k̄hxng k̄hị̀ xāc thảh̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng t̄hạ̀w mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng t̄hạ̀w (rwm thậng mĕd mam̀wngh̄imphānt̒, xạl mxn d̒ wx lnạth phī khæn, phis̄ tā cheīy, ḥe se lnạth læa t̄hạ̀w brāsil) s̄āmārt̄h k̀x h̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
        <item>C̄hạn mī xākār phæ̂ xỳāng runræng thī̀ ca h̄xy mæ̂ r̀xngrxy k̄hxng h̄xy (rwm thậng h̄xy mælngp̣hū̀, h̄xy thāk bk plāh̄mụk whelks h̄xy nāngrm læa sxs̄ h̄xy nāngrm) s̄āmārt̄h k̀x h̄ı̂ keid xạntrāy t̄hụng chīwit pt̩ikiriyā h̄līk leī̀yng kār pn peụ̄̂xn doy kār thảkhwām s̄axād cĥxn s̄̂xm thậngh̄md, kratha, phụ̄̂n p̄hiw kār prung xāh̄ār læa k̄heīyng pord trwc s̄xb khwām plxdp̣hạy s̄̀wnp̄hs̄m thī̀ chı̂ nı kār rạbprathān xāh̄ār k̄hxng c̄hạn k̄hxbkhuṇ thī̀ ch̀wy c̄hạn ca kin dị̂ xỳāng plxdp̣hạy.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Greek">
        <item>Δεν μπορώ να φάω γλουτένη (που υπάρχει στο σιτάρι, κριθάρι, στη σίκαλη και στη βρώμη). Ακόμη και ίχνη γλουτένης μπορεί να με κάνουν εξαιρετικά άρρωστο. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια. </item>
        <item>Έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στα φιστίκια. Ακόμη και ίχνη από φιστίκια μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή μου αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>Έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στο Σέλινο. Ακόμη και ίχνη από σέλινο μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στα καρκινοειδή. Ακόμη και ίχνη μαλακόστρακα (συμπεριλαμβανομένων καβούρια, αστακοί, γαρίδες, καραβίδες και γαρίδες πάστα) μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>Έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στα ψάρια. Ακόμα και μικρές ποσότητες ψαριών (συμπεριλαμβανομένων γαύρος, ο σολομός, οι σαρδέλες, ο τόνος κ.λπ.) μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στα γαλακτοκομικά. Ακόμα και μικρές ποσότητες γαλακτοκομικών (που υπάρχει στο βούτυρο, τυρί, κρέμα γάλακτος, το γάλα σε σκόνη και το γιαούρτι) μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στο λούπινο. Ακόμα και ίχνη ποσοτήτων λούπινου μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκεύη, τηγάνια, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλούμε επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται σε γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά μου για να φάει με ασφάλεια. </item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία σε Θειούχα. Ακόμα και ίχνη του διοξειδίου του θείου (θειώδη) μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στη σόγια. Ακόμα και ίχνη ποσοτήτων σόγιας μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία σε μουστάρδας. Ακόμα και ίχνη ποσοτήτων μουστάρδα μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στο σουσάμι. Ακόμα ίχνη του σουσάμι μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στα αβγά. Ακόμα και ίχνη των αυγών μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στο Nuts. Ακόμη και ίχνη ξηρών καρπών (συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κάσιους, αμύγδαλα, καρύδια, πεκάν, φιστίκι Αιγίνης, φουντουκιών και τα καρύδια Βραζιλίας) μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
        <item>έχω μια σοβαρή αλλεργία στα μαλάκια. Ακόμη και ίχνη των μαλακίων (συμπεριλαμβανομένων μύδια, σαλιγκάρια της γης, καλαμάρια, βούκινα, στρείδια και σάλτσα στρειδιών) μπορεί να προκαλέσουν μια απειλητική για τη ζωή αντίδραση. Παρακαλώ αποφύγετε τη διασταυρούμενη μόλυνση από τον καθαρισμό όλων των σκευών, τηγανιών, επιφάνειες μαγειρέματος και σανίδες κοπής. Παρακαλώ επιβεβαιώστε τα ασφαλή συστατικά που χρησιμοποιούνται στο γεύμα μου. Σας ευχαριστώ για τη βοήθειά, για να φάω με ασφάλεια.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Hindi">
        <item>मैं लस (गेहूं, जौ, राई और जई में वर्तमान) नहीं खा सकता। इससे भी ट्रेस लस की मात्रा मुझे बहुत बीमार बना सकते हैं। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं मूँगफली के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि मूंगफली की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं अजवाइन के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि अजवाइन की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं क्रसटेशियन के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहां तक ​​कि (केकड़ों, झींगा, झींगे, Scampi और झींगा पेस्ट सहित) क्रसटेशियन की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं एक गंभीर एलर्जी मछली करने के लिए है। यहां तक ​​कि( सामन, सार्डिन, ट्यूना आदि सहित) मछली की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं डेयरी के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि डेयरी की मात्रा (मक्खन, पनीर, क्रीम, पाउडर दूध और दही में मौजूद) का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं ल्यूपिन के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि वृक की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं Sulphides के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि सल्फर डाइऑक्साइड (sulphites) की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं सोया के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि सोया की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं सरसों के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि सरसों की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं तिल के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि तिल की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं अंडे के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहां तक ​​कि अंडे की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं पागल के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहाँ तक कि पागल (काजू, बादाम, अखरोट, एक प्रकार का अखरोट, पिस्ता, अखरोट और ब्राजील नट्स सहित) की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद। </item>
        <item>मैं मोलस्क के लिए एक गंभीर एलर्जी है। यहां तक ​​कि (सीपियों, भूमि घोंघे, व्यंग्य, whelks, कस्तूरी और कस्तूरा सॉस सहित) मोलस्क की मात्रा का पता लगाने के लिए एक जीवन को खतरा पैदा प्रतिक्रिया पैदा कर सकता है। सभी बर्तन, धूपदान, खाना पकाने सतहों की सफाई और बोर्डों को काटने से पार संक्रमण से बचने। कृपया सत्यापित सुरक्षित सामग्री अपने भोजन में उपयोग किया जाता है। मुझे सुरक्षित खाने के लिए मदद करने के लिए धन्यवाद।</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Portuguese">
        <item>Eu não posso comer glúten (presente no trigo, cevada, centeio e aveia). Mesmo pequenas quantidades de glúten pode fazer-me extremamente doente. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Peanuts. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de amendoim pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a aipo. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de aipo pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Crustáceos. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de crustáceos (incluindo caranguejos, lagostas, camarões, scampi e pasta de camarão) pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a pescar. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de peixe (incluindo anchovas, salmão, sardinha, atum etc.) pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Dairy. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de produtos lácteos (presentes na manteiga, queijo, creme de leite, leite em pó e iogurte) pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Lupin. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de tremoço pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a sulfuretos. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de dióxido de enxofre (sulfitos) pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a soja. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de soja pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a mostarda. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de mostarda pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Sesame. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de gergelim pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a ovos. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de ovos pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Nuts. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de nozes (incluindo caju, amêndoa, noz, pecan, pistache, avelã e castanha do Brasil) pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança. </item>
        <item>Tenho uma alergia grave a Moluscos. Mesmo pequenas quantidades de moluscos (incluindo mexilhões, caracóis terrestres, lulas, búzios, ostras e molho de ostra) pode causar uma reação fatal. Evitar a contaminação cruzada por limpar todos os utensílios, panelas, superfícies de cozinha e tábuas de corte. Por favor, verifique ingredientes seguros são usados ​​em minha refeição. Obrigado por me ajudar a comer com segurança.</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="Hungarian">
        <item> Nem tudok enni glutén (jelen búza, árpa, rozs, zab). Még nyomokban glutént tud nekem nagyon beteg. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia földimogyoró. Még nyomokban földimogyoró okozhat életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan. </item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Zeller. Még nyomokban zeller okozhat életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia rákféle. Még nyomokban a rákok (beleértve a rákot, homárt, garnélarák, scampi és garnéla paszta) okozhat életveszélyes reakció. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan. </item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia hal. Még nyomokban a hal (beleértve a szardella, lazac, szardínia, tonhal stb) is okozhat életveszélyes reakció. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Dairy. Még nyomokban a tejtermékek (jelen vaj, sajt, tejföl, tejpor, joghurt) okozhat életveszélyes reakció. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Lupin. Még nyomokban csillagfürt okozhat életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Szulfidok. Még nyomokban kén-dioxid (szulfitokat) okozhat egy életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Szója. Még nyomokban szója okozhat életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia mustár. Még nyomokban mustár okozhat életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Sesame. Még nyomokban szezám okozhat életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Tojás. Még nyomokban tojást is okozhat egy életveszélyes reakciót. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia Nuts. Még nyomokban dió (beleértve a kesudió, mandula, dió, pekándió, pisztácia, mogyoró és a brazil dió) okozhat életveszélyes reakció. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
        <item> Van egy súlyos allergia puhatestűek. Még nyomokban a puhatestűek (beleértve az éti kagylók, szárazföldi csigák, tintahal, whelks, osztrigák és osztriga szósz) okozhat életveszélyes reakció. Kereszt szennyezés elkerülése érdekében a tisztítás minden edény, serpenyő, vízmelegítők és vágódeszkák. Kérjük, ellenőrizze a biztonságos összetevőket használnak az én étel. Köszönjük, hogy segít nekem enni biztonságosan.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Albanian">
        <item> Nuk mund të hani gluten (të pranishëm në grurë, elb, thekër dhe kënaqur). Edhe gjurmë shumat e gluten mund të më shumë të sëmurë. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për kikirikë. Edhe gjurmë shumat e kikirikë mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë. </item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për Selino. Edhe gjurmë shumat e selino mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për krustaceve. Edhe gjurmë shumat e krustaceve (duke përfshirë gaforret, karavidhe, prawns, Scampi dhe paste karkaleca) mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë. </item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për të peshkuar. Edhe gjurmë shumat e peshkut (duke përfshirë anchovies, salmon, sardelet, ton etj) mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda ndaj qumështit. Edhe gjurmë shumat e qumështit (të pranishëm në gjalpë, djathë, krem, qumështi pluhur dhe kos) mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për Lupin. Edhe gjurmë shumat e ujku mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për sulfide. Edhe gjurmë shumat e dioksidit të squfurit (sulphites) mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda ndaj soje. Edhe gjurmë shumat e sojë mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për mustardë. Edhe gjurmë shumat e mustardë mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për Sesam. Edhe gjurmë shumat e susamit mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda në vezë. Edhe gjurmë shumat e vezëve mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda për arra. Edhe gjurmë shumat e arra shqeme (duke përfshirë, bajame, arre, arra, fëstëk, lajthi dhe arra Brazil) mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
        <item> Unë kam një alergji të rënda ndaj molusqeve. Edhe gjurmë shumat e molusqeve (duke përfshirë midhje, kërmij tokës, kallamar, whelks, oysters dhe salcë gocë deti) mund të shkaktojë një reagim kërcënuese të jetës. Shmangur kontaminimin kryq me pastrimin e të gjitha veglat, pans, sipërfaqet e gatimit dhe prerja bordet. Ju lutem verifikoni përbërësit të sigurta janë përdorur në ushqimin tim. Faleminderit për të ndihmuar mua për të ngrënë në mënyrë të sigurtë.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Bosnian">
        <item> Ne mogu da jedem gluten (prisutna u pšenici, ječmu, raži i zobi). Čak i u tragovima količine glutena mogu da me izuzetno loše. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na kikiriki. Čak i tragovi kikirikija može izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno. </item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Celer. Čak i tragovi celer može izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Rakovi. Čak i tragovi rakova (uključujući i rakova, jastoga, kozice, škampi i škampi paste) može uzrokovati život opasne reakcije. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno. </item>
        <item> Imam ozbiljne alergije na ribu. Čak i u tragovima količine ribe (uključujući i inćuni, losos, sardine, tuna i sl) može uzrokovati život opasne reakcije. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Dairy. Čak i tragovi mliječnih (prisutna u maslac, sir, vrhnje, mlijeko u prahu i jogurt) mogu izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Lupin. Čak i tragovi lupine može izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Sulfidi. Čak i u tragovima količine sumpor dioksida (sulfita) može uzrokovati život opasne reakcije. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Soja. Čak i tragovi soje mogu izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Senf. Čak i tragovi senfa može izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Sesame. Čak i tragovi susama može izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na jaja. Čak i tragovi jaja mogu izazvati opasne po život reakciju. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na jaja. Čak i tragovi matice (uključujući i indijski, badema, oraha, orasima, pistacija, lješnjaka i brazilski orasi) može uzrokovati život opasne reakcije. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
        <item> Imam tešku alergiju na Mekušci. Čak i tragovi mekušaca (uključujući i dagnje, zemljišta puževa, lignje, whelks, kamenice i ostriga) može uzrokovati život opasne reakcije. Izbjegavajte unakrsne kontaminacije čišćenjem sve posuđe, tave, površine za kuhanje i rezne ploče. Molimo provjerite sigurno sastojci se koriste u mom obrok. Hvala vam što ste mi pomogla da jedem sigurno.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Danish">
        <item> Jeg kan ikke spise gluten (til stede i hvede, byg, rug og havre). Selv spormængder af gluten kan gøre mig meget syg. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for jordnødder. Selv spormængder af jordnødder kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert. </item>
        <item> Jeg har en alvorlig allergi over for selleri. Selv spormængder af selleri kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for krebsdyr. Selv spormængder af krebsdyr (herunder krabber, hummer, rejer, scampi og rejer pasta) kan medføre en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert. </item>
        <item> Jeg har en alvorlig allergi over for fisk. Selv spormængder af fisk (herunder ansjoser, laks, sardiner, tun etc.) kan medføre en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for Dairy. Selv spormængder af mejeri (til stede i smør, ost, fløde, mælkepulver og yoghurt) kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for Lupus. Selv spormængder af lupin kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for Sulfider. Selv spormængder af svovldioxid (sulfitter) kan medføre en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for soja. Selv spormængder af soja kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for sennep. Selv spormængder af sennep kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for Sesame. Selv spormængder af sesam kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for æg. Selv spormængder af æg kan forårsage en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for nødder. Selv spormængder af nødder (herunder cashew, mandel, valnød, pecan, pistacie, hasselnød og paranødder) kan medføre en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
        <item> I har en alvorlig allergi over for Bløddyr. Selv spormængder af bløddyr (herunder muslinger, snegle, blæksprutter, whelks, østers og østers sauce) kan medføre en livstruende reaktion. Undgå krydskontaminering ved at rense alle redskaber, pander, madlavning overflader og skærebrætter. Kontroller sikre ingredienser bruges i min måltid. Tak for at hjælpe mig til at spise sikkert.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Estonian">
        <item> Ma ei saa süüa gluteenivaba (olemas nisu, oder, rukis ja kaer). Isegi väikeses koguses gluteeni saab teha mulle väga halvasti. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia maapähklid. Isegi jälgedena maapähklid võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult. </item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia Seller. Isegi jälgedena seller võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia koorikloomade. Isegi jälgedena koorikloomad (sh krabid, homaar, krevetid, scampi ja krevetid pasta) võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult. </item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia kala. Isegi väikeses koguses kala (sh anšoovis, lõhe, sardiinid, tuunikala jne) võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia Dairy. Isegi väikeses koguses piimatooteid (olemas või, juust, koor, piimapulber ja jogurt) võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia Lupin. Isegi jälgedena lupiin võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia Sulfiidid. Isegi väikeses koguses vääveldioksiidi (sulfitid) võivad põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia soja. Isegi jälgedena soja võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia sinep. Isegi jälgedena sinep võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia Sesame. Isegi jälgedena seesami võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia muna. Isegi väikeses koguses munade võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia pähklid. Isegi jälgedena pähklid (sealhulgas india, mandel, pähkel, pekanihikkoripuu, pistaatsia, pähkli ja Brasiilia pähklid), võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
        <item> Mul on tõsine allergia molluskid. Isegi jälgedena molluskid (sh rannakarbid, maa teod, kalmaar, Tõrikodalased, austrid ja austri kastmes) võib põhjustada eluohtliku reaktsiooni. Vältida ristsaastumist puhastamine kõik riistad, potid, toiduvalmistamiseks pindade ja lõikelaudu. Palun kontrollige ohutuid aineid kasutatakse minu sööki. Täname, et aitate mind sööma ohutult.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Icelandic">
        <item> Ég get ekki borða glúten (staðar í hveiti, bygg, rúg og höfrum). Jafnvel rekja magn af glúteni getur gert mig mjög illa. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi fyrir jarðhnetum. Jafnvel snefilmagni af hnetum geta valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða á öruggan hátt. </item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Sellerí. Jafnvel í snefilmagni sellerí getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Krabbadýr. Jafnvel í snefilmagni krabbadýrum (þ.mt krabbar, humar, rækjum, rækjum og rækju líma) geta valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða á öruggan hátt. </item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi fyrir fiski. Jafnvel snefilmagni af fiski (þ.mt ansjósu, lax, sardínur, túnfisk o.fl.) geta valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Dairy. Jafnvel í snefilmagni selinu (Present í smjöri, osti, rjóma, mjólk duft og jógúrt) getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Lupin. Jafnvel í snefilmagni lúpínu getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi súlfíðum. Jafnvel í snefilmagni brennisteinsdíoxíðs (súlfít) geta valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Soya. Jafnvel í snefilmagni soja getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Sinnep. Jafnvel í snefilmagni sinnepi getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi Sesame. Jafnvel í snefilmagni sesam getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi fyrir eggjum. Jafnvel snefilmagni af eggjum getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi fyrir hnetum. Jafnvel snefilmagni af hnetum (þ.mt cashew, möndlu, Walnut, pecan, pistasíu, heslihnetu og Brasilía hnetur) getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða óhætt.</item>
        <item> Ég er með alvarlega ofnæmi lindýrum. Jafnvel í snefilmagni lindýrum (þ.mt kræklingi, land snigla, smokkfisk, whelks, ostrur og ostrusósu) getur valdið lífshættulegri viðbrögð. Forðastu víxlmengun með því að hreinsa öll áhöld, pönnur, elda yfirborð og skurðbretti. Gakktu úr skugga um öruggar hráefni eru notuð í máltíð mína. Þakka þér fyrir að hjálpa mér að borða örugglega.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Latvian">
        <item> Es nevaru ēst lipeklis (klāt kviešu, miežu, rudzu un auzu). Pat izsekot summas lipekli var darīt man ļoti slikti. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret zemesriekstiem. Pat nelielu zemesriekstu var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši. </item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret Selerijas. Pat nelielu selerijas var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret vēžveidīgajiem. Pat izsekot daudzumu vēžveidīgo (ieskaitot krabjiem, omāriem, garnelēm, scampi un garneļu pastas), var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši. </item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret zivīm. Pat nelielu zivju (ieskaitot anšoviem, lasis, sardīnes, tuncis uc) var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret piena. Pat izsekot daudzumu piena (kas atrodas sviests, siers, krējums, piena pulvera un jogurts), var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret lupīnas. Pat nelielu lupīnu var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret sulfīdi. Pat nelielu daudzumu sēra dioksīda (sulfīti) var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret sojas. Pat nelielu daudzumu sojas var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret sinepēm. Pat nelielu sinepes var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret Sesame. Pat nelielu sezama var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret olām. Pat nelielu daudzumu olu var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret riekstiem. Pat nelielu riekstu (tostarp Indijas rieksti, mandeļu, valriekstu, pekanriekstu, pistāciju, lazdu riekstu un Brazīlijas rieksti), var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
        <item> Man ir smaga alerģija pret mīkstmieši. Pat nelielu molusku (ieskaitot mīdijas, zemes gliemeži, kalmāri, Bruņcepurgliemeži, austeru un austeru mērci), var izraisīt dzīvībai bīstamu reakciju. Izvairītos no savstarpējas inficēšanās ar tīrīšanas visas trauki, pannas, virtuves virsmas un griešanas dēļi. Lūdzu, pārbaudiet drošas sastāvdaļas tiek izmantotas manā maltīti. Paldies, ka palīdzējāt man ēst droši.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Slovak">
        <item> Nemôžem jesť lepok (prítomný v pšenici, jačmeň, raž a ovos). Dokonca aj stopové množstvo lepku môže robiť ma veľmi zle. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na arašidy. Aj stopové množstvo arašidov môže viesť k život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne. </item>
        <item> Mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na zeler. Aj stopové množstvo zeleru môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na kôrovce. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo kôrovcov (vrátane kraby, homáre, krevety, krevety a krevetovou pastou) môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne. </item>
        <item> Mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na ryby. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo rýb (vrátane ančovičiek, losos, sardinky, tuniak atď) môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na mliečne výrobky. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo mliečnych potravín (ktoré sú vo maslo, syry, smotana, sušené mlieko a jogurt) môžu spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na Lupina. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo vlčí bôb môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na sulfidy. Aj stopové množstvo oxidu siričitého (siričitany) môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na sóje. Aj stopové množstvo sóje môže viesť k život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na horčicou. Aj stopové množstvo horčice môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na Sesame. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo sezamu môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na vajíčka. Aj stopové množstvo vajec môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na orechy. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo orechov (vrátane kešu, mandle, orech, pekanové, pistácie, lieskové orechy a para orechy), môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
        <item> mám ťažkú ​​alergiu na mäkkýšoch. Dokonca aj stopové množstvo mäkkýšov (vrátane mušlí, suchozemských ulitníkov, chobotnice, surmovky, ustríc a ustricová omáčkou), môže spôsobiť život ohrozujúce reakcie. Zabránilo krížovej kontaminácii čistenie riadu, panvy, povrch varenie a rezanie dosiek. Je potrebné overiť bezpečné ingrediencie sú používané v mojom jedle. Ďakujeme vám za pomoc mi jesť bezpečne.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Swedish">
        <item> Jag kan inte äta Gluten (finns i vete, korn, råg och havre). Även spårmängder av gluten kan göra mig mycket sjuk. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot jordnötter. Även spårmängder av jordnötter kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta på ett säkert sätt. </item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot selleri. Även spårmängder av selleri kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot kräftdjur. Även spårmängder av kräftdjur (inklusive krabbor, hummer, räkor, jätteräkor och räkpasta) kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta på ett säkert sätt. </item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot fisk. Även spårmängder av fisk (inklusive ansjovis, lax, sardiner, tonfisk etc.) kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot Dairy. Även spårmängder av mejeriprodukter (som finns i smör, ost, grädde, mjölkpulver och yoghurt) kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot Lupin. Även spårmängder av lupin kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot sulfider. Även spårmängder av svaveldioxid (sulfiter) kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot soja. Även spårmängder av soja kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot senap. Även spårmängder av senap kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot Sesame. Även spårmängder av sesam kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot ägg. Även spårmängder av ägg kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot nötter. Även spårmängder av nötter (inklusive cashew, mandel, valnöt, pecan, pistasch, hasselnöt och paranötter) kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att du hjälper mig att äta säkert.</item>
        <item> Jag har en allvarlig allergi mot mollusker. Även spårmängder av blötdjur (inklusive musslor, mark sniglar, bläckfisk, whelks, ostron och ostronsås) kan orsaka en livshotande reaktion. Undvik korskontaminering genom att städa alla redskap, kastruller, matlagning ytor och skärbrädor. Bekräfta säkra ingredienser används i min måltid. Tack för att hjälpa mig att äta säkert dig.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Slovenian">
        <item> Ne morem jesti gluten (prisotno v pšenico, ječmen, rž in oves). Tudi v sledovih količine glutena, lahko me zelo bolan. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na arašide. Tudi sledove arašidov lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti. </item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na zelene. Tudi sledove zelene lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Raki. Tudi majhne količine rakov (vključno z raki, jastogi, kozice, škampi in kozice pasta), lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti. </item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na ribe. Tudi majhne količine rib (vključno z inčuni, losos, sardine, tuna, itd), lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Dairy. Tudi majhne količine mleka in mlečnih izdelkov (ki so prisotne v maslo, sir, smetano, mleko v prahu in jogurt), lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na lupin. Tudi sledove lupine lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Sulfidi. Tudi majhne količine žveplovega dioksida (sulfite) lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na sojo. Tudi sledove soje lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Gorčično. Tudi sledove gorčico lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Sezam. Tudi sledove sezama lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na jajca. Tudi sledove jajc lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Nuts. Tudi sledove oreškov (vključno indijski, mandljev, orehov, pecan, pistacija, lešnikov in brazilskih orehov), lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
        <item> I imajo hudo alergijo na Mehkužci. Tudi sledove mehkužcev (vključno s školjkami, kopenskih polžev, lignje, whelks, ostrige in ostrig omako), lahko povzroči smrtno nevarne reakcije. Preprečevati navzkrižno kontaminacijo s čiščenjem vsa orodja, posode, kuhanje površine in rezanje plošč. Preverite varne sestavine, ki se uporabljajo v mojem obroku. Hvala, ker ste mi pomagali, da varno jesti.</item>
    </string-array>


</resources>